PERSONAL INFORMATION

Anca - Paula NECHITA



Iasi (Romania)

(+40) 742578171

apnec.web@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ancapaula

Sex Female | Date of birth 05/09/1986 | Nationality Romanian | Driving Licence B

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A full professional with over 12 years of experience in various industries and multicultural environments. Master in Organizational Management, with expertise in database analysis with a strong power of observation, organized, determined, and committed to the company's business priorities and revenue goals. Focused on continuing professional development, also an enthusiastic traveller, and a continuous learner with a "can - do" attitude.

WORK EXPERIENCE

11/2019-06/2020

Technical Assistant / Recruiter for Nuclear Power Plant

Areva International, Eurajoki (Finland)

- -daily use of CMS Software for creating Periodic Tests, Work Orders and punctual updates requested by email;
- -compiling data into weekly report 4WLA and indicating to Planning &Scheduling, which are the WO's to be executed in the following 4 weeks;
- -managing the budgeting and recruitment process for PSM department in strong collaboration with Procurement and Cost Control departments (from opening positions until arrival on site);
- -creation, validation and tracking of purchase requests (for manpower, materials, trainings, etc.);
- -regular reporting and KPI's;
- -support in all analytical tasks;
- -management of staff time sheets;
- -organizing and attending meetings and trainings, writing procedures, and all secretarial works (PSM staffing 85 employees).

Business or sector Oil & Energy

12/2018-09/2019

Student - Full Time Finnish language course

Valmenuskeskus OY Finland, Pori (Finland)

- intensive language course, as part of foreigners' integration program;
- -Language Certificate A 2.2 proficiency.

05/2016-05/2018

Forecast Specialist/Sales Analyst

Zeelandia Romania, lasi (Romania)

- -drafting, checking and validation of documents for the export of goods and finished goods to NON-EU country;
- -team coordinator responsible for expiration risk reduction and forecasting process improvement;
- -coordinating, implementing and applying ABC analysis method in sales, supply chain and production departments for inventory optimization;
- -monthly sales volume forecast (portfolio of 600 items), resulting in a 40 % out of stock drop in 2017 compared to 2016;
- -calculating forecast accuracy using excel, identifying and implementing new methods to improve the process, creating procedures for streamline the forecast supply production flow;
- -analysing market trends and seasonality;
- -analysis-based delisting proposals for non-performing items;
- -implementing and use of sales forecast software.

Business or sector Food

05/2012–05/2016 Sales and Marketing Customer Service Representative

Brikston Construction Solutions, Iasi (Romania)

- -direct communication with customers, providing support and accuracy of the requested information;
- -documents preparation and verification for export of products to EU and NON EU countries;
- -solving contractual penalties through cancellation, based on clear justification and evidence;
- -sending proforma invoices according to the agreed commercial conditions, tracking their traceability up to the collection, invoicing orders;
- -responsible for the accuracy of the registered payment instruments and for the various financial statements sent at client's request (ex: due debts, invoices to be issued, accounts receivable, sales discounts, etc.);
- -inventory-management and products custody (excel reports to clients and sales managers, by request);
- -promoting products according to the company strategy.

Business or sector Constructions

07/2011-05/2012

Customer Support in IT Services for UK

SCC Romania, Iasi (Romania)

- -checking, validating and entering data in the system, updating database and procedures, processing the orders and monitoring the deliveries;
- -identifying details regarding suppliers' product categories, prices, product availability and delivery dates;
- -processing orders in the internal system and placing them on supplier's webpage, contacting suppliers, creating part codes within deadlines.

Business or sector IT Services

08/2008-06/2011

Risk Administrator

Viitorul Cooperative Bank, Iasi (Romania)

- -making monthly analysis of compliance limits for each risk and draw up recommendations on measures to be taken in case of exceeding them, for both headquarter and working point;
- -centralizing and analysing reported risk data and creating accurate reports for management;
- -informing Risk Management Committee on the risk indicators evolution;
- -direct reporting to the audit of the National Bank of Romania;
- -coordinating training sessions for employees regarding the identification, evaluation and control of operational risk.

Business or sector Banking

10/2006-07/2007

Insurance referent

Generali Insurance, Iasi (Romania)

- -providing necessary information regarding damage compensation;
- -supporting clients in filling damage compensation files;
- -preparing the daily schedule, permanently updating the database;
- -performing all administrative tasks;
- -archive management.

Business or sector Financial and insurance activities

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2008-2010

Master Degree in Organizational Management (MBA)

Alexandru Ioan Cuza University, Iasi (Romania)

2005–2008 Bachelor degree in Economics

Alexandru Ioan Cuza University, Iasi (Romania)

2001–2005 College degree - Technician in finance and commerce

Economic & Administrative College, Iasi (Romania)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Romanian

Foreign language(s)

English
Finnish
German

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C1	C1	C1
A2	A2	A2	A2	A2
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

Communication skills

-great communication and technical skills, gained through my vast experience in working with people, solving difficult tasks and also implementing and managing processes.

Job-related skills

- -managing the staff budget and recruitment process for PSM department in Olkiluoto Nuclear Power Plant:
- -project member "Sales Excellence Product Portfolio Management", developed by House of Performance (NL);
- -project member in applying of ABC analysis method, considering the organizational particularities;
- -CAPEX for implementing and using a forecast software;
- -product Status Portfolio Management for 600 SKU's;
- -project coordinator "Loss-limiting actions caused by expiry".

Organizational skills

- ability to adapt and learn quickly;
- -multi-tasking, focus, task prioritization;
- -fast decision making, flexible, analysis and synthesis capacity;
- -repetitive tasks resistance, details attention, work with figures;
- -good time management, communicative, motivated, positive thinking, team player;
- -responsibility, correctitude, seriousness, trustworthiness, persuasive, open-minded.

Digital skills

- -Microsoft Office Suite: advanced Excel (pivot tables, VLOOKUP, formulas, advanced filters, dashboard charts, etc.), Power Point, Word and Microsoft Outlook);
- -ERP's: CMS, Scala, Synchron, Smart Forecast, etc.;
- -Introduction in Programming (with Python) Wantsome 2020;
- -Microsoft Certification " Data Analysis using Excel".